# **Abhilash Shah**

(+91)8097062698 • 9

- 98abhilash@gmail.com
- Mumbai
- linkedin.com/in/shah-abhilash/

- github.com/98abhilash
- · kaggle.com/abhilashshah
- https://98abhilash.github.io/

#### **SUMMARY**

A driven Machine Learning Engineer with over two years of experience building and developing Computer Vision and Deep Learning solutions. Has expertise in gathering and analyzing data, improving or building models, and aligning them with business needs. At Celusion Technologies successfully developed a computer vision-based Passive Liveness Model with a precision score of 85%. Eager to bring experience in developing Machine Learning based solutions to your company.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

Data Analysis, Machine Learning Algorithms, Computer Vision and Deep Learning Frameworks

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, NumPy, Flask and ML Ops

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Celusion Technologies** | Thane, Maharashtra

October 2020 - Present

Software Developer - Machine Learning

Working as a Machine Learning engineer developing Deep Learning based solution in the fraud detection domain

- Designed and developed end-to-end ML Pipelines within company for the projects
- Solely in charge of developing a Passive Liveness Detection Model based on computer vision with precision of about 85%
- Included myself in projects based on **Object Detection and OCR** within the company
- · Researched and executed various Modelling Techniques with satisfactory results

#### **INTERNSHIP**

**Celusion Technologies** | Thane, Maharashtra

October 2019 - March 2020

Machine Learning Intern

Worked as a Machine Learning Engineer Intern

• Work revolved around **Research and Initial Development** of Object Detection based Models

#### **EDUCATION**

**IIIT-Bangalore** | Maharashtra, IN

October 2021 - Present

Executive PG Programme in Machine Learning & AI [Specialization: Deep Learning with ML Ops]

| Maharashtra, IN

Online Program from IIIT-Bangalore

Coursework: Statistics, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, NLP and ML Ops

**Mukesh Patel School of Technology and** 

August 2016 - April 2020

**Management Engineering | NMIMS** 

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

CGPA: 3.23 / 4.00

Coursework: Data Structures, Database Management, Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence

#### **PROJECTS**

- Cotton Plant Disease Detection using Object Detection Models [Academic] [TensorFlow, SSD, Faster RCNN] - 2019
  - Collected, Cleaned and Annotated more than 1500+ images of cotton plant leaves from the farms of Maharashtra.
  - Devised a Hybrid approach of using two Object Detection model for the detection of Diseased part of the leaves.
- Automatic Ticket Classification [Academic] [NLTK, Scikit-Learn, Topic Modelling] [Link] 2022
  - Developed a Model to classify customer complaints based on the product/service.
  - Comparative Analysis were performed on different models like Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Random Forest and Naive Bayes.
  - Used the concept of Topic Modelling along with Logistic Regression in order to classify Tickets.

### • Gesture Recognition - Smart TV [Academic] [TensorFlow, Conv3d, LSTM] [Link] - 2022

- Developed a Gesture Recognition Model based on Conv3d to control Smart TV using hand gesture instead of remote.
- Comparative Analysis were performed on different model architecture such as TimeDistributed CNN and LSTM
- Performed Hyperparameter Tuning in order reduce overfitting of the Models on the data.

### • Skin Cancer Detection [Academic] [TensorFlow, CNN] [Link] - 2022

- Developed a CNN model to detect Melanoma skin cancer on the data maintained by International Skin Imaging Collaboration (ISIC).
- Performed Data Augmentation, handled Class Imbalanced and compiled and compared different CNN models in order to find the accurate model.

#### • Telecom Churn Prediction [Academic] [Scikit-Learn, PCA, Logistic Regression] [Link] - 2022

- Developed a Logistic Regression based model in order to predict churn for a Telecom company.
- Performed extensive EDA, Feature Engineering and PCA on the data in order to find best possible features to train on.

## Bike Sharing Demand Prediction [Academic] [EDA, Scikit-Learn, Multiple Linear Regression] [Link] -2022

- Developed a Multiple Linear Regression model in order to predict demand for shared bikes.
- Performed Recursive Feature Elimination (RFE) in order to remove data points that could mislead the regression model resulting in bad predictive performance.